William C. Sexton Papers
William C. Sexton Papers
1946-1969
1962-1969
Sexton, William C.
0.5 linear ft.
American journalist. Collection contains biographical material, correspondence, printed material, speeches and writings.
2989493
Biographical History
William C. Sexton (1929- ) is an American journalist. Born in 1929, Sexton attended Culver Military Academy and the University of North Carolina. He was with the United Press bureau from 1947 to 1959 (with a two-year absence for military service), then in 1961 joined the American Press Institute, eventually becoming its associate director. He was managing editor for the Louisville Courier-Journal and editor of World Book News Science Service.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William C. Sexton Papers consist of biographical material, correspondence, printed material, speeches and writings.
Biographical material contains news releases from various significant points in Sexton's career.
Correspondence, most of which is photocopies of outgoing letters, contains relatively few letters but they are of notable length and substance. An index to correspondents appears at the end of this inventory.
Printed material contains a few items from 1946-1962 for which no drafts are present, only the published version.
Speeches include addresses given at professional conferences, workshops, and other occasions.
The majority of Writings appear to be pieces written for trade or professional journals; topics include information retrieval for the mass market, operation of news departments, staff meetings, newspaper style, and similar.
Arrangement of the Collection
Correspondence, printed material and speeches are arranged chronologically. Writings are arranged alphabetically by title.
Related Material
has substantial holdings relating to journalism and journalists. Please refer to for a complete listing.
Subject and Genre Headings
Journalism; Sexton, William C.; Journalism -- United States.; Journalists -- United States.; Newspaper editors -- United States.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Manuscripts for publication.; Speeches (documents); Journalists.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Acquisition Information
Gift of William C. Sexton, 1968-1969.
Inventory
- Biographical material
  - Miscellaneous (Box 1)
- Correspondence
  - [General], 1965-1968 (Box 1)
  - Confidential memos, 1965; 1968 (Box 1)
- Printed material
  - Miscellaneous, 1946; 1960,; 1962 (Box 1)
- Speeches
  - American Association of Sunday and Feature Editors, 1962, Aug 20 (Box 1)
  - Theta Sigma Phi workshop, Cleveland, Ohio, 1963, Aug (Box 1)
  - Sigma Delta Chi, University of Rhode Island, 1963, Dec 7 (Box 1)
  - New England Daily Newspapers Association, Boston, 1964 (Box 1)
  - High School Press Day, Troy, New York, 1964 (Box 1)
  - Sigma Delta Chi, professional chapter, Louisville, Kentucky, 1964, May 5; notes for address (Box 1)
- Writings
  - African Seminar report, 1965 (Box 1)
  - Bigness - bad for a newspaper or merely inevitable?, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Church's own computer, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Education for communicators: The second century, 1968; first and second drafts; 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Forty-two hours in a pressure cooker: The world's longest staff meeting, 1969 (Box 1)
  - Information retrieval for the mass market, Jun 1968 (Box 1)
  - Introducing...World Book science service, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Is there a better way to cover the news?, 1967 (Box 1)
  - I've always known we'll get men there" John Jurgenson, 1968 (Box 1)
  - National and international coverage in local newspapers, 1963; notes for discussion (Box 1)
  - On becoming a professor, 29 Dec 1962 (Box 1)
  - On the importance of being heard, Nov 1967 (Box 1)
  - Organization and operation of the news department, Sep 1966 (Box 1)
  - Style, The newspaper in the 1970s: a revolution?, 1968 (Box 1)
  - Systems analysis in the newsroom, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Why people read newspapers: a new non-McLuhan theory, Sep 1967 (Box 1)
  - WBESSI (World Book Encyclopedia Science Service, Inc.), 1967 (Box 1)
  - Writing in depth: the long and short of it, May 1968 (Box 1)
Index to correspondence
Arpan, Floyd (professor, Indiana University) 1967 Dec 21
Associated Press International, miscellaneous memos 1965, 1968
Ballotti, Geno A. (managing editor, Daedalus) 1967 Nov 7
Benson, [ ] (University president) 1967 Feb 15
Bingham, Barry (Louisville Courier-Journal) 1965 Nov 24 1966 Jun
Bogart, Leo (Bureau of Advertising, ANPA) 1967 Nov 9
Furlong, Bill 1967 Nov 6
Hines, William (Washington Evening Sun; Chicago Daily News bureau 1968 Feb 6 1968 Feb 12
Isaacs, Norman E. (Louisville Courier-Journal) 1966 Feb 1 1966 Aug 5
Low, George M. (NASA Manned Spacecraft Center, Houston) 1967 Feb 13
MacKinnon, Cyrus (Louisville Courier-Journal) 1966 Dec 3
Montys 1968 Feb 23
Murray, J. Edward (Arizona Republic) 1968 Jul 23
Larry Pryor 1968 Dec 15 (incoming) 1968 Dec 19